Hello, in this and the next few videos I'm going to be giving a overview of COOL the
您好，在这段视频和接下来的几个视频中，我将给出一个很酷的概述
programming language in which you'll be writing a compiler. Cool is the Classroom
您将用来编写编译器的编程语言。教室里很酷
Object Oriented Language and the acronym of course, is COOL. And the unique design
当然，面向对象语言和缩写是很酷的。和独特的设计
requirement for COOL is that the compiler has to be able to be written in a
Cool的要求是编译器必须能够用
relatively short period of time. We only have one quarter, or in some cases, a
时间相对较短。我们只有一个季度，或者在某些情况下，
semester for students to write the compilers. And so COOL has to be
学期供学生编写编译器。所以必须要很酷
implementable quickly. And actually since it's used primarily for teaching
可快速实施。实际上，因为它主要是用来教学的
compilers, the number of COOL compilers in the world vastly exceeds, the number of
编译器，世界上最酷的编译器的数量远远超过
COOL programs. So, there many, many more compilers have been written, thousands of
很酷的节目。因此，已经编写了许许多多的编译器，数以千计
compilers, maybe tens of thousands of compilers have been written for COOL, but
编译器，也许数以万计的编译器是为炫酷而编写的，但是
probably only some dozens, or hundreds COOL programs. And so, it's probably the
可能只有几十个，或者几百个很酷的程序。所以，这很可能是
only language, in existence for which this is true, That, that, the number of
只有一种存在的语言，对它来说是真的，那，那，数量
compilers actually exceeds the number of programs, but it does Tell you about the
编译器实际上超过了程序的数量，但它确实告诉您
main design requirement. It's much more important in COOL that the compiler be
主要设计要求。在Cool中，更重要的是编译器
easy to write then that it be easy to write programs in. And so there are some
容易编写，那么编写程序就容易了。所以这里有一些
quirks in the language, Things that have been done specifically to make it easier
语言中的怪癖，特别是为了让它变得更容易而做的事情
to implement where that wouldn't take away from the, the teaching value of the, of
在不会剥夺，的，的教学价值的情况下，
the language. But that would make it inconvenient to use the language on a
语言。但是这会使在
day-to-day basis as a working programmer. So, what is in the language? Well it's,
作为一名工作的程序员进行日常工作。那么，语言里有什么呢？嗯，这是，
we've tried to design it so that it will give you a taste of modern notions of
我们试着设计它，这样你就能领略到现代观念的滋味。
extraction static typing reuse through inheritance, automatic memory management.
提取静电打字复用，通过继承，自动内存管理。
And there's actually a few more things that we'll talk about when we come to
实际上，当我们谈到这一点时，我们还会谈到更多的事情
them. But many things are left out. We're not gonna be able to put everything in the
他们。但是很多东西都被遗漏了。我们不可能把所有东西都放到
language and have it be implementable quickly. We'll be able to cover some
语言，并使其能够快速实现。我们将能够覆盖一些
things in lectures, but unfortunately, there'll even be some interesting language
但不幸的是，甚至会有一些有趣的语言
ideas that we won't be able to get to in this class. So the course project is to
我们在这节课上学不到的想法。所以课程项目是
build a complete compiler. And specifically you're going to compile COOL
构建一个完整的编译器。具体地说，你要编译酷
into MIPS assembly language. So MIPS is a real instruction set, It was for a machine
转换成MIPS汇编语言。所以MIPS是一个真正的指令集，它是为一台机器准备的
that was designed in the 1980's. And there is a simulator for MIPS that runs on just
它是在20世纪80年代设计的。而且有一个MIPS模拟器，它只运行在
about any kind of hardware. And so this makes the, the whole project very
关于任何一种硬件。所以这使得整个项目非常的
portable, We can run your compiler, or you can generate MIPS assembly language and
可移植，我们可以运行您的编译器，或者您可以生成MIPS汇编语言和
then that MIPS assembly language can be simulated on just about whatever kind of
那么MIPS汇编语言几乎可以在任何类型的
machine you have access to. The project is broken up into five assignments. First
你有权使用的机器。这个项目被分成五个作业。第一
you're gonna write a COOL program. And that program itself will be an interpreter
你要写一个很酷的程序。而该程序本身将是一个解释器
to give you a little bit of experience with writing a simple interpreter. And
给您一点编写简单解释器的经验。和
then the compiler itself will consist of the four the phases that we discussed
然后编译器本身将由我们讨论的四个阶段组成
lexical analysis, parsing, semantic analysis and code generation. And all of
词法分析、解析、语义分析和代码生成。以及所有的
these phases, I should emphasize are [inaudible] compatible. Meaning that we
我要强调的是，这些阶段是[听不见的]兼容的。这意味着我们
have separate implementations, separate reference implementations of each of
有单独的实现，每个都有单独的引用实现
these. And so for example, when you are working on semantic analysis, you will be
这些。举个例子，当你在做语义分析时，你会
able to take the lexical analysis, parsing, and code generation components
能够使用词法分析、解析和代码生成组件
from the reference compiler and plug your semantic analysis into that. Framework
并将您的语义分析插入其中。框架
and, and test it against the reference components. And so this way if you have
并对照参考组件对其进行测试。这样一来，如果你有
trouble with one component or aren't sure that your components is working very well
一个组件出现故障或不确定您的组件是否工作正常
you won't have a problem in working on a different component because you'll be able
使用不同的组件不会有问题，因为您可以
to test that independently. And finally there's no required optimization
来独立测试这一点。最后，不需要进行必要的优化
assignment, But we do have some suggestions for optimizations that you can
任务，但我们确实有一些优化建议，您可以
do. And many people have written optimizations for COOL. And so this is an
做。而且很多人已经为酷编写了优化。所以这是一个
optional assignment if you're interested in learning something about program
如果您有兴趣学习一些有关程序的知识，请选择作业
optimization. So, let's write the simplest possible COOL program. And the first thing
优化。所以，让我们写一个尽可能简单的酷程序。第一件事就是
to know is that COOL source files, and in the extension dot CL for COOL, and you can
要知道是酷源文件，并在扩展名中点CL为酷，可以
use whatever editor you like to write your programs. I happen to use Emacs, you can
使用您喜欢的任何编辑器来编写程序。我碰巧用的是Emacs，你可以
use some other editor if you like. And every COOL program has to have a class
如果您愿意，可以使用其他编辑器。而且每个很酷的程序都必须有一个类
called main. And let's talk about that business in a second. So a class
叫做Main。我们待会再谈这件事。所以一堂课
declaration in COOL begins with the key word, class, Followed by the name of the
Cool中的声明以关键字class开头，后跟
class, So in this case, main, Followed by a pair of curly braces And inside the
类，因此在本例中为main，后跟一对大括号，并在
curly braces is where all the stuff that belongs to the class goes, And every class
大括号是属于类的所有内容的位置，每个类
declaration must be terminated by a semi-colon. So a program consists of a
声明必须以分号结束。因此，一个程序由一个
list of class declarations. Each class declaration terminated by a semi-colon. So
类声明列表。每个类声明都以分号结尾。所以
that's the structure of a class. And now we need this class to actually do
这就是班级的结构。现在我们需要这个类来实际做
something so we're going to have a method in this class, and let's call the method
所以我们在这个类中会有一个方法，让我们调用该方法
main. In fact the main method of the main class must always exist. This is the
主干道。事实上，Main类的Main方法必须始终存在。这是
method that's run to start the program and furthermore this method must take no
方法来启动程序，而且此方法必须不带
arguments. So the empty argument list for the main method is always empty. And let's
争论。因此，Main方法的空参数列表始终为空。让我们
say the main method its body always goes in a pair of curly braces. So the main
说主要的方法，它的主体总是放在一对花括号里。所以主要的
method always goes inside curly braces. And a class consists of a list of such
方法始终放在大括号内。而一个类由这样的列表组成
declarations. And again, those declarations must all be separated by
声明。同样，这些声明都必须用
semicolons. So in, or terminated, excuse me, by semicolons. So in this case, we
分号。所以，请原谅，用分号来表示，或以分号结尾。所以在这种情况下，我们
only have one method in the class. But still has to have its semi-colon and now
类中只有一个方法。但还是要有分号，现在
we can say what we want the method actually do so this is the place for the
我们可以说出我们想要的，方法实际上是这样做的，所以这是
code for the method goes and let's just have the simplest possible method the one
该方法的代码是这样的，我们只使用可能的最简单的方法，即
that just event evaluates to the number one. Okay, so [inaudible] an expression
那个公正的事件被评为第一名。好的，所以[听不见]一个表情
language, which means that wherever a piece of code can go, you can put an
语言，这意味着在一段代码可以到达的任何地方，都可以将一个
arbitrary expression, any expression can go there there's no explicit return
任意表达式，任何表达式都可以到那里，没有显式返回
statement for a method. It's just a value of the method body is the value of the
方法的语句。它只是方法体的一个值，即
methods. So in this case we just put the number one in there, and that will be the
方法。在这种情况下，我们只需将数字1放在那里，这将是
value of this method when we run it. So let's save that. And now we can try
此方法在运行时的值。所以我们还是省省吧。现在我们可以试着
compiling this simple program, so how do we compile the compiler is called a COOL c
编译这个简单的程序，那么我们如何编译编译器被称为很酷的c
for the COOL compiler and you just give the COOL compiler a list of COOL source
对于Cool编译器，您只需给Cool编译器一个Cool源代码列表
files. So in this case there's just one file 1.CL hit enter and ooh we got a
文件。在本例中，只有一个文件1.CL按Enter键，哦，我们得到了一个
syntax error so we have to come back and fix that and the error said at or near the
语法错误，因此我们必须回来修复该错误以及在
open curly brace on line three there's a mistake. And I know what the mistake is,
打开三号线的花括号，肯定是弄错了。我知道错在哪里，
because I'm a competent COOL programmer, at least somewhat competent COOL
因为我是一个能干的酷程序员，至少有点能干的酷
programmer. Cool methods must declare their return type. So we need to put a
程序员。Cool方法必须声明它们的返回类型。所以我们需要把一个
type here. And the syntax for the declaration is to put a colon after the
在此键入。声明的语法是在
name of the method and the argument list, and then the name of a type. And since
方法和参数列表的名称，然后是类型的名称。既然
we're returning the number one for this program for sorry, for this method we
我们返回此程序的第一个数字表示抱歉，对于此方法，我们
might as well say that the main method is going to return an integer, So save that,
不妨说Main方法将返回一个整数，所以保存它，
Go back to our compilation window and let's compile the program again. And this
返回到我们的编译窗口，让我们重新编译程序。还有这个
time it compiles successfully. And now if we look in our directory we see that there
它编译成功的时间。现在如果我们查看我们的目录，我们会发现
is a new file called 1.s. That's the assembly code for the program one. And now
是一个名为1.s的新文件。这是程序一的汇编代码。而现在
we could try to run this code. And the, The, the Mitch simulator is called spin,
我们可以试着运行这段代码。这个米奇模拟器叫Spin，
and it just takes a, assembly file to, to simulate, And so we just give it one
它只需要一个汇编文件来模拟，所以我们只给它一个
[inaudible] hit enter and it will run. A whole bunch of stuff is printed out. But
[听不见]按Enter，它就会运行。一大堆东西都被打印出来了。但
as you can see, it says part way down that the COOL program successfully executed, so
正如你所看到的，它说在下面的一部分，很酷的程序成功地执行了，所以
that's good, and then afterwards there are some statistics and things like number of
这很好，然后有一些统计数据，比如
instructions executed, a number of loads and stores, a number of branches, those
执行的指令、加载和存储的数量、分支的数量等
things would be interesting if we're worried about performance if we were to
如果我们担心性能的话，事情会很有趣，如果我们
say working on the optimization of the compiled code, but we're not doing that
比方说致力于编译代码的优化，但我们不会这样做
right now. We're just running programs. And we can see if this program works. So
现在就来。我们只是在运行程序。我们可以看看这个程序是否有效。所以
the program ran. It terminated successfully. But it didn't actually
程序运行了。它已成功终止。但它实际上并没有
produce any output. And that's because we didn't ask it to produce any output, If we
产生任何输出。这是因为我们没有要求它生产任何产品，如果我们
want to have output. We have to go back and modify the program again. So, so what
想要有输出。我们必须回去重新修改程序。所以，那又怎么样
this program does currently, is that it just returns its value but that, but
这个程序目前所做的是，它只返回它的值，但是
nothing is done with that value. It's not printed out or anything like that. If you
用这个值什么也做不了。它不是打印出来的，或者类似的东西。如果你
wanted to have something printed out in a COOL program, you have to do that
想要在很酷的程序中打印出一些东西，你必须这么做
explicitly. So there's a special class built in, a primitive class called IO. And
明确地说。所以内置了一个特殊的类，一个名为IO的原始类。和
we can declare, what's called a attribute of this class, it will be a IO attribute
我们可以声明，这个类的一个属性，它将是一个IO属性
and it will be called I, okay and I will be a object that we use to do IO. So now
它将被称为I，好的，我将是我们用来做IO的一个对象。所以现在
in our, main method, Here we could add a call to out-string, I dot out-string is
在我们的main方法中，我们可以在这里添加对out-string的调用，我点出字符串是
how we invoke a method. Okay so out-string is a method of the IO class so we use I to
我们如何调用方法。好的，out-string是IO类的一个方法，所以我们使用i
invoke that method and then we can pass it a string that we want printed out on the
调用该方法，然后我们可以向它传递一个字符串，我们希望将该字符串打印到
screen. So for example we could say hello world. Okay, And now, we have to decide
屏幕。例如，我们可以说hello world。好的，现在，我们必须决定
what to do, with our, with our number one there. And let me show you one more
怎么办，我们的，我们的头号在那里。让我再给你们看一个
feature of COOL. Let's leave the one there, and let's make it part of a
酷炫的特点。让我们把那个留在那里，让我们把它变成
statement block. So a statement block consists of a sequence of expressions
挡路声明。因此，挡路语句由一系列表达式组成
separated by semicolons. And you can have any number of expressions, and the
用分号隔开的。您可以有任意数量的表达式，并且
semantics of a statement block or an expression block is to just evaluate the
挡路语句或表达式挡路的语义是只计算
expressions in order. And the value of the block is the value of the last expression.
表达式按顺序排列。而挡路的价值就是最后一个表达式的价值。
But now, a statement or an expression block has to be included in its own set of
但现在，挡路的声明或表达必须包含在它自己的
curly braces. Okay, so that now is a valid COOL program so let me just read this for
花括号。好的，现在这是一个有效的很酷的程序，让我读一下这个
you so the body of the program is a block of expressions. The first one, executes. A
你看，节目的主体是一个挡路的表情。第一个，执行。一个
out string call to the object I, which is going to print hello world for us. And
输出字符串调用对象i，它将为我们输出hello world。和
then the second one evaluates to one, which is the value of the entire of the
然后，第二个求值结果为1，这是
entire method. Okay, actually I should say it's the value of the block, okay, and
整个方法。好的，其实我应该说这是挡路的价值，好的，而且
then because the block is the body of the method the value of the block becomes the
因为挡路是方法的主体，所以挡路的价值就变成了
value of the entire method, So one will be returned from this method call. So let's
值，因此此方法调用将返回一个。所以让我们
save this. Go back over here and let's compile this again. So, Looks like I
省省吧。回到这里，让我们再编译一遍。所以，看起来我
failed to save it. Let's compile this and we see we have a syntax error. And so it
保存失败。让我们编译这段代码，我们会发现有一个语法错误。就这样，它
says on line four, we have a syntax error at or near our closing curly brace. And
在第四行，我们在右花括号或其附近有一个语法错误。和
the problem here is that a statement block, or expression block consists of a
这里的问题是，挡路语句或表达式挡路由
series or a sequence of expressions terminated by semi-colons, and we forgot
以分号结尾的一系列或一系列表达式，但我们忘记了
to terminate the last expression in the sequence by its semi-colon, So we have to
以分号结束序列中的最后一个表达式，因此我们必须
add that. And now we should be able to compile this, and lo and behold it
再加上那个。现在我们应该可以编译这个了，看看它
compiles correctly, and then we can run it. And now we see, oh we got another
编译正确，然后我们就可以运行它了。现在我们看到了，哦，我们又有了一个
mistake. So we have an, when the program ran it complained that we have a
弄错了。所以我们有一个，当程序运行的时候它抱怨说我们有一个
dispatched void. So that on line four, our dispatch was to an object that didn't
派遣无效。所以在第四行，我们的调度对象不是
exist. And, you can see the dispatch call right here to I, and it doesn't exist,
存在。而且，你可以看到调度电话就在这里打给我，但它并不存在，
because, in fact, we forgot to allocate an object for I. So here we declare I to be
因为，事实上，我们忘了为I分配一个对象，所以我们在这里声明I为
of type IO, but that doesn't actually create any objects. That just says that it
类型IO，但这实际上不会创建任何对象。这就说明了这一点
creates a variable name I but I doesn't actually have a value. So if you want I to
创建一个变量名i，但我实际上没有值。所以如果你想让我
actually have a value, we have to initialize it to something. So we can
实际上有一个值，我们必须将其初始化为某个值。这样我们就可以
initialize it to a new IO object. And new here, is the way you allocate new objects
将其初始化为新的IO对象。这里的新功能是分配新对象的方式
in COOL and new always take a type argument so in this case were creating a
在COOL和NEW中，始终接受类型参数，因此在本例中我们创建了
new object in type IO and were assigning it To this object i. And notice here that
类型IO中的新对象，并将其分配给此对象i。请注意，
I is a, is a, is what would be called a field name in Java. It's what we call an
I is a，is a，在Java中被称为字段名。这就是我们所说的
attribute in COOL. So, so these are the data el, the data elements of the, of the
属性设置为COOL。所以，这些是数据el，，的数据元素
class. And so the class can have both of names of things that are so, attributes or
班级。因此，该类可以同时具有属性或属性这两个事物的名称
fields that hold values as well as methods that can perform computation. [sound]
保存值的字段以及可以执行计算的方法。[声音]
Let's save this and switch back. And now we'll compile this again. So and it still
我们先把这个保存起来，然后再换回去。现在我们再编译一遍。所以它仍然
compiles. And now we can run it. And now it runs, and low and behold, as you can
编译。现在我们可以运行它了。现在它跑起来了，低低地看着，就像你所能看到的那样
see down there third line from the, the top, it prints out hello world. And that
看看下面第三行，从上面开始，它打印出hello world。那就是
looks a little bit ugly because the, the successful execution message is on the
看起来有点难看，因为成功执行的消息在
same line as our hello world message. So let's fix that. Let's come back over here.
和我们的问候世界信息一样。所以让我们来解决这个问题。我们回到这里来吧。
And in our string here we can add a new line. Okay at the end of the string, so
在我们的字符串中，我们可以添加新的一行。好的，在字符串的末尾，所以
backslash N is how you write a new line character in the string. Save that, come
反斜杠N是在字符串中写换行符的方式。省省吧，来吧
back over here let's compile. So if you don't know Unix bang will repeat the
回到这里，让我们编译一下。所以如果你不知道unix bang会重复
previous expression the previous command that began with the same prefix that you
上一个表达式以与您相同的前缀开头的上一个命令
type after the bang. So I want to run the last command that began with C which is to
在砰的一声之后键入。所以我想运行最后一个以C开始的命令，即
compile and then I want to run the last command that began with S which is to run
编译，然后我想运行最后一个以S开头的命令，该命令将运行
spin. And now we can see there it is all nice hello world is on a line by itself.
旋转。现在我们可以看到，一切都很美好，你好，世界本身就在一条线上。
Let's continue now, let's [sound] clear all this out [sound]. So let me just show
现在让我们继续，让我们[声音]把这一切都弄清楚。所以让我来展示一下
you a few variations on the same program. What I'm going to do here is just rewrite
你可以看到同一节目的几个变种。我在这里要做的就是重写
it in a couple of different ways. So I just illustrate a couple of features of
有几种不同的方式。因此，我只说明了以下几个功能
COOL and get you more familiar with the syntax, and also just show some
很酷，让您更熟悉语法，还可以展示一些
alternative ways to do the same thing. So you know this, this. A block here of, of
用不同的方式来做同样的事情。所以你知道这个，这个。一份挡路的，一份
expressions is kind of a clumsy way to, to implement the Hello World program. So
表达式是实现Hello World程序的一种笨拙的方式。所以
let's get rid of that. Let's get rid of the, the block. Let's get rid of the one
我们把它扔掉吧。我们把这个挡路去掉吧。我们把那个扔掉吧
here at the end. Okay, let's just make the statement body a single expression again,
就在这里的尽头。好的，让我们再把语句体变成一个单独的表达式，
and, and now the problem we're going to have is that the types won't match. But
现在我们面临的问题是类型不匹配。但
just to illustrate that, let me show it to you so let's do COOL C of one dot CL, and
为了说明这一点，让我展示给你们看，所以让我们来做一个点CL的冷C，还有
you'll see here that in complains that the inferred return type of the IO of the
您将在此处看到，在投诉中推断的
method main does not conform to the declared return type INT. So coming back
方法Main不符合声明的返回类型int。所以回来的时候
over here, the, to the program, The, the compiler figured out that this expression,
在这里，这个，给这个程序，这个，这个编译器算出来这个表达式，
I dot out string, yields an object of type IO. So it returns the i object as the
我划掉字符串，生成IO类型的对象。因此它将I对象作为
results evaluating this expression. And that does not match the type it. And so
计算此表达式的结果。这与它的类型不符。因此，
naturally, the compiler says, hey, something's wrong with the types. Well,
自然，编译器会说，嘿，类型有问题。井,
that's easily repaired. We can just change the return type or the main method to say
那很容易修好。我们只需更改返回类型或Main方法即可
it returns something of type IO. So let's go back over here and see if that now
它返回IO类型的内容。所以让我们回到这里，看看现在
works. So, we compile the program. And then we run spin on the output, and yes,
很管用。所以，我们编译了这个程序。然后我们对输出运行Spin，是的，
everything still works as expected. Now, We don't have to be so specific about the
一切仍按预期进行。现在，我们不需要这么具体地
type over here, since we're not actually using the result of the method body for
在这里键入，因为我们实际上没有将方法体的结果用于
anything. I mean, the program just exits once it prints the string. We could have
什么都行。我的意思是，一旦打印出字符串，程序就会退出。我们本可以
allowed ourselves more flexibility here. We could've just declared the result type
允许我们在这里有更大的灵活性。我们可以只声明结果类型
of main to be of type Object. So Object is the root of the class hierarchy in COOL.
Main的类型为Object。因此，对象是COOL中类层次结构的根。
Every other class is a subclass of Object. So let's come back over h, let's save this
每隔一个类就是Object的子类。所以让我们回到h，让我们留着这个
first. And then we can come back over to our compilation window. We can compile it.
第一。然后我们可以回到编译窗口。我们可以编译它。
And we can run it and it still works. So now another thing we can do if we want, is
我们可以运行它，它仍然有效。现在，如果我们愿意，我们可以做的另一件事是
we could observe. Here that this attribute that we declare, this field I isn't really
我们可以观察。在这里，我们声明的这个属性，这个字段我实际上不是
necessary. Here we, we allocate, you know we have a special name I when the main
这是必要的。在这里我们，我们分配，你知道我们有一个特别的名字，我主要的时候
object is constructed to run the program, a new [inaudible] object is allocated to I
对象来运行程序，则会将一个新的[听不见]对象分配给i
and then that gets used in the main method. We can actually just do all of
然后在main方法中使用它。我们实际上可以做所有的
that inside the main method itself by just allocating a new [inaudible] object right
在main方法本身内部，只需分配一个新的[听不见的]对象权限
here and then calling out string on that object. Alright, So this should also work.
在这里，然后调用对象上字符串。好的，这应该也行得通。
And let's check it out. So it compiles. And lo and behold, it rots. Alright, So
让我们来看看这个。所以它会编译。看哪，它腐烂了。好的，那么
coming back over here let's illustrate one more, or a couple more things that we
回到这里，让我们再来说明一件事，或者几件事，我们
could do. So, we could also say that [inaudible] inherits From IO. So we have
可以的。所以我们也可以说[听不见]是从IO继承过来的。所以我们有
to have the IO functionality somewhere in order to call the out string method. So we
在某个地方拥有IO功能，以便调用输出字符串方法。所以我们
have been doing that by creating a separate object of type IO. But now we can
我一直在通过创建一个单独的IO类型的对象来做到这一点。但现在我们可以
say well just the main object is itself. And something that has all the
可以说，主要的客体就是它本身。一些东西拥有所有的
capabilities of IO by inheriting from IO. And if you've seen any [inaudible]
通过继承IO来实现IO的功能。如果你看到任何[听不见]
language before this will be a familiar concept. So main here gets all the
在此之前的语言将是一个熟悉的概念。所以这里的Main得到了所有
attributes and methods of IO, in addition to whatever attributes and methods of its
IO的属性和方法，以及其
own that it will have. And now Instead of, of having to allocate a new IO object in
承认它将会拥有。现在，不必在中分配新的IO对象
order to call out string, we can just invoke it on self, Which is the name of
为了调出字符串，我们可以只在self上调用它，它是
the current object when the main method runs In other languages self is called
Main方法在其他语言中运行时的当前对象Self被调用
this. Okay, and so let's we saved it, so let's go over and compile this. So it
这。好的，我们把它保存起来，然后再编译一下。就是这样
compiles, it compiles and, and it runs, right? So last example here, we don't have
编译，编译，然后运行，对吗？所以这里的最后一个例子，我们没有
to name self actually in this dispatch. There's a feature that allows us to call a
在这篇报道中提到了赛尔夫的名字。有一项功能允许我们调用
method without explicitly naming the object on which it's dispatched and
方法，而不显式命名它被调度到的对象，并且
defaults to self, so if no object is named in a dispatch then it's just a dispatched
缺省为self，因此如果在调度中没有命名对象，则它只是一个调度的
self. So this should also work. [sound], And indeed it does. So that concludes our
赛尔夫。所以这也应该行得通。[声音]，确实是这样。所以我们的节目到此结束
first example. In the next couple of videos we'll look at some more complex
第一个例子。在接下来的几个视频中，我们将看到一些更复杂的内容
examples of COOL programming.
很酷的编程示例。